Résumé Tilman Porschütz



They/Them
Born 1984 Zwickau, Germany
Living in Vienna, Austria
tilman@porschuetz.de

dev.mandymozart.com
www.porschuetz.de

also known as: Mandy Mozart

Tilman is a motivated and experienced *front-end developer* specializing in **user interfaces** and immersive experiences.

Their focus lies in bridging human needs and digital realities by combining state-of-the-art technologies with **responsible design** and **UX/UI**. As a developer, Tilman has built single-page applications, websites, interactive installations, and apps. As a **CTO** and **requirements engineer**, Tilman is a reliable **team player** who has led interdisciplinary teams of up to 15 people, working with agencies, startups, and corporations.

Tilman discusses and challenges their experiences with peers through regular attendance at conferences and in their research work as an *awarded media artist*, *contemporary composer*, and *enthusiast media scientist*. This universal approach allows them to maintain a nuanced perspective on a market in constant flux. They also contribute to Open Source projects and share knowledge with non-profit organizations.

Education

2004–2011

Bauhaus-University Weimar

Diploma, Visual Communication

Hongik University Seoul

Visiting student, Visual Design

Experience

Self-Employed

2014-2023 Freelance

froyouandyourcustomers GmbH 2017–2023 *Fulltime*

Vienna Struggle Media GmbH 2019–2021 *CTO*, *Co-Founder*

negativelabs

2018-2021 Contractor

Messerli AG

2013-2014 Contractor

Lingoda GmbH

2012-2013 Fulltime

WEAREPICTURES uG

2012-2017 CTO, Co-Founder

Contract work as a digital consultant, and developer for startups, NGOs & mid-size businesses in DACH.

Consultant, UI/UX architect and frontend developer for major Austrian and international clients.

Streaming platform and on-sight production company during Covid-19.

Boutique web shops for design focused clients in DACH.

Visualisations, construction planing, prototypes and design of trade show booths & show rooms for global brands.

Developing front-end for interactive language learning class rooms and learning materials.

Digital studio for trade show booths and interaction design.

Techstack

Languages

TypeScript, Javascript, Dart, CSS, SASS, Python, Java, PHP, C#, Rust

Frameworks

NextJS, React, ThreeJS, Svelte, Django, Angular, Flutter, Spring Boot, .NET

Game Engines

Unity, Unreal Engine, PixiJS, ThreeJS

CMS

Prismic, Sanity, Bloomreach Experience, Wordpress, Woocommerce, SAP Hybris, Confluence, KeystoneJS, Strapi

Infrastructure

Docker, AWS, Git

Databases

PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB,

Utilities

Figma, Sketch

Protocol

WebRTC, WebSockets